A journey out of darkness into light
The Physician is a adventure, drama, history film directed by Philipp Stölzl.
England, 1021.
Rob Cole, a boy born in a miserable mining town, swears to
become a physician and vanquish disease and death.
His harsh path of many years, a quest for knowledge besieged by countless challenges and sacrifices, leads him
to the remote Isfahan, in Persia, where he meets Ibn Sina, the greatest healer of his time.
Rob Cole, played by Tom Payne.
Ibn Sina (Avicenna), played by Ben Kingsley.
Barber, played by Stellan Skarsgård.
Shah Ala ad Daula, played by Olivier Martinez.
Rebecca, played by Emma Rigby.
Karim, played by Elyas M'Barek.
The Physician (German: Der Medicus) is a 2013 German historical drama
film based on the novel of the same name by Noah Gordon.
The film, co-written and directed by Philipp Stölzl, focuses on an orphan from
an 11th-century English town whose mother died of side sickness.
The boy vows to study medicine and decides to travel to Persia.
The film stars Tom Payne, Ben Kingsley (as physician Ibn Sina), Stellan
Skarsgård, Olivier Martinez, and Emma Rigby in lead roles.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, persia, jew
persecution, historical figure, religious fundamentalism.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.